Transcript and translation
from 99meemo99 http://youtu.be/oUArQW09Two
Sung by نسمة محجوب (Nesma Mahgoub)
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
الثلج الليلة كالصحراء
Ath'thalju al'laya'ta kas'sahra'
The snow tonight is a sand desert
not a footprint to be seen
لم تلمسه اقدام
lam talmas'hu aqdam
that hasn't been touched by feet
A kingdom of isolation,
مملكة للحيارى
Mamlaka'tun lil'hayara
A kingdom for the bewildered
and it looks like I'm the queen
أحكمها بسلام
ahkumu'ha bi'salam
that I rule in peace
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
الريح تعوي مثل العاصفة داخلي
Ar'rihu ta'wi mithla al'asifati dakhili
The wind is howling like a storm inside me
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
كيف تختفي؟ حاولت جاهدة
Kayfa takhtafi? Hawaltu jahida
How to make it go? I tried hard
Don't let them in, don't let them see
لا تكشفي سر الجليد
La takshifi sir al'jaleed
Don't disclose the secret of the snow
Be the good girl you always had to be
كوني كما شعبك يريد
Kuni kama sha'buki yureed
Be what your people want you to be
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
تخفىي الإحساس . كى يجهلوا
Tukhfi al'ehsas kay yajhalu
The girl who conceals her feelings so they don't know
Well, now they know!
قد عرفوا
Qad a'rafu!
But [now] they know!
Let it go, let it go!
اطلقي سرك
Atliqi sirraki
Make your secret known
Can't hold it back any more!
لن أتحمل العذاب
Lan ata'hammal al'athab
I won't take the agony any more
Let it go, let it go!
اطلقي سرك
Atliqi sirraki
Make your secret known
Turn away and slam the door!
اغلقي خلفك الابواب
Aghliqi khalfaki al'abwab
Close the doors behind you
I don't care what they're going to say
لا اخشى كل ما سيقال
La akh'sha kulluama sa'yuqal
I don't fear all what will be said
Let the storm rage on
اطلقي العنا ن
Atliqi al'anan!
Go ahead, unleash!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
الثلج لا يشعرني باكتئاب
Ath'thalju la yush'e'runi bikti'ab
Snow does not depress me
It's funny how some distance
المشكلات ستصغر
Al'mushkilatu satas'ghur
The problem will get smaller
Makes everything seem small
لو نراها من بعيد
Law naraha min ba'eed
If we see it from far away
And the fears that once controlled me
والخوف الذى تملكني
Wa al'khawf al'lathi tamallakani...
And the fear that took over me...
Can't get to me at all!
لم يعد منه مزيد
... lam ya'ud min'hu mazeed!
... there is no more of it!
It's time to see what I can do
قد حان الوقت لانتصارات
Qad han al'waqtu lin'tisarat
The time has come for victories
To test the limits and break through
كى اختبر كل القدرات
Kay akhtabira kul al'qudrat
To test all [my] capabilities
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
بلا حدود تمنعني
Bi'la ho'dudin tamna'o'ni
With no boundaries to limit me
I'm free!
إمضي
Emdi!
Go ahead!
Let it go, let it go!
اطلقى سرك
Atliqi sirraki
Make your secret known
I am one with the wind and sky
توحدي مع الاكوان
Tawah'hadi ma'a al'akwan
Unite with the universes
Let it go, let it go!
اطلقى سرك
Atliqi sirraki
Make your secret known
You'll never see me cry
لن ابكي بعد الآن
Lan abkiya ba'ad al'aan
I will no longer cry
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
ارضي هنا . وبها سأبقى
Ardi huna, wa bi'ha sa'abqa
Here is my land, and on it, I shall stay
Let the storm rage on...
اطلقي العنان
Atliqi al'anan!
Go ahead, unleash!
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
فقوتي تسري من الهواء إلى الصخور
Fa'quwwati tasri min al'hawa'i e'la al'sukhur
My power flurries through the air into the rocks
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
و روحي كلولب ثلجى يلمع مثل النور
Wa ruhi ka'lawlabin thaljiyyin yal'ma'u mithl an'noor
And my soul is a snow spiral beaming in the light
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
وتتبلور فتكون قذيفة من جليد
Wa tata'balwaru, fa'takun qathifatan min jaleed
Then it crystallizes, so it becomes a blast of ice
I'm never going back
انا حتمنا لن اعود
Ana hatman lan a'oud
I will definitely not go back
The past is in the past!
الماضي, بيدأ صار!
Al'madi ba'eidan sar!
The past has become far!
Let it go, let it go!
لن يعود . لن يعود
Lan ya'oud! Lan ya'oud!
It won't come back! It won't come back!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
وسأشرق مثل النور
Wa sa'ushriqu mithl an'noor
And I will shine like a flare of light
Let it go, let it go!
لن يعود . لن يعود
Lan ya'oud! Lan ya'oud!
It won't come back! It won't come back!
That perfect girl is gone
فقدت برائتي
Faqd'tu bara'a'ti
I lost my naiveness
Here I stand in the light of day
ها أنا الآن اقف أمام الناس
Ha ana al'aan, aqifu a'mam an'nas
Here I am now, standing in front of people
Let the storm rage on!
وسط الرياح
Wast ar'riyah
In the midst of the wind
The cold never bothered me anyway.
الثلج لا يشعرني بإكتئاب
Ath'thalju la yush'e'runi bikti'ab
Snow does not depress me